<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop">
  <id>steam.desktop</id>
  <name>Steam</name>
  <summary>Application for managing and playing games on Steam</summary>
  <developer_name>Valve Corporation</developer_name>
  <description>
    <p>Steam is an Internet-based digital distribution platform developed by Valve Corporation offering digital rights management (DRM), multiplayer, and social networking. Steam provides the user with installation and automatic updating of games on multiple computers, and community features such as friends lists and groups, cloud saving, and in-game voice and chat functionality. The software provides a freely available application programming interface (API) called Steamworks, which developers can use to integrate many of Steam's functions into their products, including networking, matchmaking, in-game achievements, micro-transactions, and support for user-created content through Steam Workshop.</p>
    <p>Though initially developed for use on Microsoft Windows, versions for OS X and Linux operating systems were later released. Applications whose main functions are chatting and shopping have also been released for iOS and Android mobile devices. The Steam website also replicates much of the storefront and social network features of the stand-alone application.</p>
    <p>As of September 2015, over 6,400 games are available through Steam, including over 2,300 for OS X and 1,500 for Linux. The service has over 125 million active users. Steam has had as many as 12.5 million concurrent users as of November 2015. The Steam platform is considered to be the largest digital distribution platform for PC gaming; in November 2009, Stardock estimated it at 70% and then later, in October 2013, it was estimated by Screen Digest that 75% of games bought online are downloaded through Steam.</p>
  </description>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://steamcommunity.com/groups/SteamClientBeta/discussions/0/</url>
  <url type="help">https://help.steampowered.com/</url>
  <url type="homepage">https://steampowered.com/</url>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image>https://repo.aosc.io/appdata/screenshots/Steam-1.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://repo.aosc.io/appdata/screenshots/Steam-2.png</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
</component>
