<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright 2014 Richard Hughes <richard@hughsie.com> -->
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>HP-hplip.desktop</id>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-2.0 and MIT and BSD-2-Clause</project_license>
  <name>HPLIP Graphic Tools</name>
  <summary>HPLIP GUI tools and GUI part of other HPLIP tools</summary>
  <description>
    <p> The HPLIP GUI subpackage provides graphic tools for the management of supported HP printers. These tools are not capable to run without graphical user interface, or they have unremoveable dependency on GUI modules. </p>
    <ul> 
      <li>hp-check - tool for checking dependencies,</li>
      <li>hp-print - UI frontend for printing,</li> 
      <li>hp-systray - tool for monitoring HP device status,</li>
      <li>hp-toolbox - HP Device Manager,</li>
      <li>hp-devicesettings - device settings tool,</li>
      <li>hp-faxsetup - fax device setup tool,</li>
      <li>hp-linefeedcal - line feed calibration tool,</li>
      <li>hp-makecopies - tool for making copies for HP AiO and MFP devices,</li>
      <li>hp-printsettings - printer settings tool,</li>
      <li>and hp-wificonfig - Wifi/Wireless/802.11 configuration tool for connecting HP printer to Wifi</li>
    </ul>
    <p>This subpackage also provides GUI parts for tools shipped by the HPLIP base package:</p>
    <ul>
      <li>hp-align - cartridge alignment tool for HP inkjet printers,</li>
      <li>hp-clean - printhead cleaning tool for HP inkjet printers,</li>
      <li>hp-colorcal - color calibration tool for HP inkjet printers,</li>
      <li>hp-diagnose_queues - auto config tool for HP MFP to diagnose queues configuration,</li>
      <li>hp-fab - simple fax address book,</li>
      <li>hp-firmware - tool for download firmware for HP device,</li>
      <li>hp-info - tool for querying a HP printer about static model information, dynamic status information, and CUPS printer queue settings,</li>
      <li>hp-plugin - HP proprietary plugin download and install tool,</li>
      <li>hp-sendfax - PC send fax tool for HP MFP printers,</li>
      <li>hp-setup - tool for installing printers and faxes in the CUPS spooler,</li>
      <li>hp-testpage - tool for printing testpage,</li>
      <li>and hp-unload - tool for accessing inserted photo cards on supported HP printers (alternative for devices without USB mass storage support or for access to photo cards over a network).</li>
    </ul>
    <p>The tools that do not need GUI for its functionality must be run with the '-i' option when the hplip-gui package is not installed.</p>
    <p>The Launch button does not work because this subpackage is set of tools and it is not set which tool to launch from Gnome Software.</p>
  </description>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/zdohnal/hplip/master/hplip1.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/zdohnal/hplip/master/hplip2.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/zdohnal/hplip/master/hplip3.png</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
  <url type="homepage">http://hplipopensource.com/</url>
  <update_contact>richard_at_hughsie.com</update_contact>
</component>
